<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title></title>
		<description></description>
		<link></link>
		<atom:link href="/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
			<item>
				<title>Rewind: 2013</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;This was a year of changes for me. I moved to Palmas - TO to work, the job itself, living only with friends and my girlfriend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve encountered rocks on the path, big ones, crazy ones, but in the end they were all good because I&#39;ve grown up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It all started in october 2012 , with a job exam for civil servant, which turns out me and 3 more friends have passed, but we were just called to work at march 2013, pretty much time, isn&#39;t it? Well, This was a life changer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The whole new life helps to grown up a bit more, get more responsabilities, learn new stuff about life. Also, as I worked, I experienced things that made me think more about the kind of future I want. I&#39;m now sure where I wanna go, I&#39;m gonna do everything to get there. Thus, from this year that&#39;s about to start I&#39;m gonna be dedicated to improve myself, learn a lot, start cool projects, to not get stuck without action (zombie mode), investing in new material and tools, just for the sake of a better future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I already have a basic plan for 2014, one of them started this december, the other ones is upcoming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2013 was for sure a great year for me and I&#39;m gonna work hard to make 2014 better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy new year!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2013 05:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>/post/2013/12/rewind-2013</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/post/2013/12/rewind-2013</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Retrospectiva: 2013</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Este foi um ano de mudanças para mim. I me mudei para Palmas - TO a trabalho, o próprio trabalho, viver somente com amigos e minha namorada e mais recentemente apenas com minha namorada.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve encountered rocks on the path, big ones, crazy ones, but in the end they were all good because I&#39;ve grown up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It all started in october 2012 , with a job exam for civil servant, which turns out me and 3 more friends have passed, but we were just called to work at march 2013, pretty much time, isn&#39;t it? Well, This was a life changer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The whole new life helps to grown up a bit more, get more responsabilities, learn new stuff about life. Also, as I worked, I experienced things that made me think more about the kind of future I want. I&#39;m now sure where I wanna go, I&#39;m gonna do everything to get there. Thus, from this year that&#39;s about to start I&#39;m gonna be dedicated to improve myself, learn a lot, start cool projects, to not get stuck without action (zombie mode), investing in new material and tools, just for the sake of a better future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I already have a basic plan for 2014, one of them started this december, the other ones is upcoming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2013 was for sure a great year for me and I&#39;m gonna work hard to make 2014 better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy new year!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2013 05:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>/post/2013/12/retrospectiva-2013</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/post/2013/12/retrospectiva-2013</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Menos</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Recentemente percebi uma coisa, por mais simples que seja um objeto/serviço que preciso, busco todas as possibilidades que me dão, praticidade, simplicidade, design e, claro, tenha um bom preço. Mesmo que seja apenas uma carteira, lá estou eu, pesquisando, me informando, tentando pegar a melhor possível.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Isso ocorre também no meu aprendizado, porém, tendo a procrastinar depois de um tempo. Sinto como estivesse parado flutuando sem poder fazer nada, inútil. Acho que isso continua ocorrendo pelo fato de eu querer muitas coisas ao mesmo tempo, acabo ficando sem fazer nada.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Agora, acabei de notar, que devo ter menos coisas que tenha a possibilidade de me tirar o foco. Como faço muita coisa no computador, que é meu principal aliado e também vilão, tenho que diminuar a dependência, e usá-lo de forma mais focada.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Um navegador com várias páginas abertas, tende a te fazer querer ler várias coisas e acaba que você não termina de ler nem uma propriamente.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Minimizar as distrações&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Email, redes sociais, e vários outros são hoje apresentados de forma integrada aos sistemas operacionais, trazendo uma enxurrada de notificações a todo instante. Reduzir ou até remover essas notificações, pode trazer um benefício muito grande e certamente aumentará o seu foco e, consequentemente, a produtividade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;É interessante, também, diminuir (se possível) a quantidade de coisas pra fazer. Uma vez que se tem poucas coisas, você pode focar nelas melhor e trazer melhores resultados a tarefa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;São poucas dicas, mas que pode fazer uma enorme diferença se feitas corretamente. Alguma dica?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2013 10:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>/post/2013/12/menos</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/post/2013/12/menos</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Copiando seus heróis: Uma maneira (ligeiramente) diferente de aprendizado</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Sempre há por aí blogs, palestras, entre outros, falando sobre como se tornar um excelente desenvolvedor/designer mostrando várias listas com sites e livros para guiá-lo, o que às vezes são realmente boas fontes. Mas eu quero falar sobre uma forma diferente para você se tornar bom em algo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recentemente eu li um livro de Austin Kleon, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Steal-Like-Artist-Things-Creative/dp/0761169253/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1377275103&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=Steal+Like+an+Artist%3A+10+Things+Nobody+Told+You+About+Being+Creative&quot;&gt;Steal Like an Artist: 10 Things Nobody Told You About Being Creative&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, um livro muito bom com bons conselhos. Como o próprio título mostra, é sobre criatividade, porém uma parte do livro me tocou de verdade, ele mostrou um caminho para o aprendizado.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eu acredito que o que nos fez quem somos hoje foi o que tentamos conquistar ontem. Nós definimos um meta a ser alcançada, e então, vamos em busca dela. Às vezes isto é consciente, às vezes não. Por exemplo, se você quer se tornar um desenvolvedor, você se cerca de livros, aplicações, segue alguns desenvolvedores na internet, etc. Isso é basicamente o que a maioria de nós fazemos, mas com o tempo, nós paramos de seguir aquele espírito. Nós emperramos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ao invés disso, nós deveriamos continuar a seguir nossos sonhos, continuar a ser curioso, &quot;stay hungry and foolish&quot; como disse Steve Jobs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Copie seus heróis&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Um dos conselhos é &lt;strong&gt;&quot;Fake it &#39;til you make it&quot;&lt;/strong&gt;, algo como, finja até que você consiga. É como eu escrevi acima, mas não que você vá mentir, é mais como um exercício de inspiração.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Start copying what you love. Copy copy copy copy. At the end of the copy you will find your self.” —Yohji Yamamoto&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nós não começamos nossas vidas como o senso de bom e mal, nós nem mesmo sabemos quem somos. Nós aprendemos fingindo ser nossos heróis, nós aprendemos copiando.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Usar ferramentas que eles usam, ler o que eles leem. Assim, buscar fazer o que eles fariam ao invés de o que eles fazem hoje. Emulá-los. Dessa forma, você estará fazendo do seu próprio jeito. Você quebrará o espelho e seguirá adiante.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Faça isso como todos seus heróis, misture-os, capte deles o que eles tem de melhor para oferecer, então aplique isso na sua vida, internalize.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No momento em que você começa a pensar como seus heróis você deixa de &quot;imitá-los&quot; e começa a ser o que uma vez você desejou.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Faça um bom trabalho! =)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2013 18:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>/post/2013/11/copiando-seus-herois</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/post/2013/11/copiando-seus-herois</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Copying our heroes: A (slightly) different way of learning</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;There&#39;s always blog posts, talks, etc, about how to become a great developer/designer showing you tons of lists with sites and books to guide you, which is also really good. I want to show you a different approach for getting good at something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently I read a book by Austin Kleon, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Steal-Like-Artist-Things-Creative/dp/0761169253/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1377275103&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=Steal+Like+an+Artist%3A+10+Things+Nobody+Told+You+About+Being+Creative&quot;&gt;Steal Like an Artist: 10 Things Nobody Told You About Being Creative&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, a really nice book with great advices. As the title says, it is about creativity, but a part of the book really touched me, it shows a path for learning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe that what made us who we are today was what we tried to achieve yesterday. We set in our heads a level to reach, and then go after it. Sometimes it is conscious, sometimes it&#39;s not. For example, if you want to become a developer, you surround yourself with books, applications, follows some dev guys on the internet. That&#39;s what most of us do, but with time we don&#39;t follow this spirit anymore. We get stuck.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, we should continue pursuing our dreams, still be curious, stay hungry and foolish as Steve Jobs liked to say.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Copy your heroes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the advices is &lt;strong&gt;&quot;Fake it &#39;til you make it&quot;&lt;/strong&gt;. It&#39;s something like I write above, but you are not going to lie, actually, you will inspire yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Start copying what you love. Copy copy copy copy. At the end of the copy you will find your self.” —Yohji Yamamoto&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We don&#39;t start our lives with all the sense of good and bad, we don&#39;t even know who we are. We learn by pretending to be our heroes, we learn by copying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using tools they use, read what they read. Then look for doing what they would do instead of what they do today. Emulate them. This is when you are doing your own thing. You break the mirror and go further.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do this with all of your heroes, mix them, get the better you see from every hero you have, than apply this in your life, internalize.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you start thinking like your heroes is when you stop faking and start being what once you desire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do a great job! =)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2013 17:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>/post/2013/11/copying-our-heroes</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/post/2013/11/copying-our-heroes</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>On dreams and money</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s very common here where I live people talking about work less or not even work and get money for this. Government all-life-jobs are seen exactly this way and more, you can hardly get fired, so why worry about to work after all this?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I work for the government (not for very long, I hope) but I want to make some difference, develop some useful tools, create good apps that can lead to a better work. Right now it&#39;s really hard to find someone else here that have this vision since it seems everyone is blinded for the &quot;easy&quot; money that come in the end of the month. There&#39;s lack of initiative, people talk about money like they were dreams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this environment, sometimes it&#39;s hard to move forward keeping motivated because what makes me move on, what my passion is, is to build with a nice team good apps that help people to do something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The funniest (or saddest?) part is when some of this &quot;Money guys&quot; tells you they have a dream, and then the talk about that dream, but he keeps the same, I mean, doing nothing to achieve the dream. Maybe the have a giant &lt;a href=&quot;http://alistapart.com/articles/banishing-your-inner-critic/&quot;&gt;inner critic&lt;/a&gt;. When that happens, I hardly talk because what it looks to me is that they just want money and workless jobs. &quot;How can I argue with someone like this?&quot;, I ask myself, until somedays ago I wouldn&#39;t do anything, but I&#39;m now experimenting to make my point of view worth a thought. Maybe I might unblind someone, maybe not. It is tough and sometimes a wanna say &quot;Wake up! Life isn&#39;t just money. Live it!&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We need to keep in our heads is that life passes and we&#39;ll not stay here for too much time. So think more about doing things you like, you passions, you dreams and less about money. Take risk, change of state, go out of your comfort zone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you do things you like, money will come eventually.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of that makes me try change this, change of city, learn more, take risks, get a job where I can build awesome stuff, innovate, have a team. Well, in the end, do what I love.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2013 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
				<link>/post/2013/09/on-dreams-and-money</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/post/2013/09/on-dreams-and-money</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Rails Forum Relaunched</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s great to see again a forum that was huge coming back. This days we have &lt;a href=&quot;http://stackoverflow.com&quot;&gt;stack overflow&lt;/a&gt; which is great, but it has a limitation that forums are built for: &lt;strong&gt;discuss&lt;/strong&gt;. Discuss is a key for keeping moving forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really enjoy this return. I hope it can turns again into a place for great discussions and friendship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/railsforum.png&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;The new Rails Forum&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2013 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
				<link>/post/2013/08/rails-forum-relaunched</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/post/2013/08/rails-forum-relaunched</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Nginx, Unicorn and multiple Rails apps</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s really easy to make a rails app run using &lt;a href=&quot;http://unicorn.bogomips.org/&quot;&gt;unicorn&lt;/a&gt; + &lt;a href=&quot;http://nginx.org/en/&quot;&gt;nginx&lt;/a&gt;, but when it comes to multiple apps, things get a lot harder, well, at least that&#39;s what I thought.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/unicorn.png&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I want is to make the root (&lt;em&gt;&quot;/&quot;&lt;/em&gt;) folder a place on the server where you can put &lt;strong&gt;HTML&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;PHP&lt;/strong&gt; and use subdirectories like &lt;em&gt;&quot;/app1&quot;&lt;/em&gt;, for exemple, to provide a rails app. Doing this correctly, makes a lot easier for me to deploy others apps using folders instead of http ports. It was really hard to find this better/easier way to run multiple rails applications and that&#39;s what makes me want to share with you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this post I&#39;m going to show you how to make your server run rails on subdirectory. For this tutorial, I&#39;m using &lt;strong&gt;Ruby 2.0 &lt;/strong&gt;and&lt;strong&gt; Rails 4.0&lt;/strong&gt;. I suppose you already have nginx and unicorn installed. So, let&#39;s get started!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In you nginx.conf file we are going to make nginx point to a unicorn socket:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;
upstream unicorn_socket_for_myapp {
  server unix:/home/coffeencoke/apps/myapp/current/tmp/sockets/unicorn.sock fail_timeout=0;
}
&lt;/pre&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Then, with your server listening to port 80, add a location block that points to the subdirectory your rails app is (this code, must be inside server block):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;
 location /myapp/ {
    try_files $uri @unicorn_proxy;
  }
 
  location @unicorn_proxy {
    proxy_pass http://unix:/home/coffeencoke/apps/myapp/current/tmp/sockets/unicorn.sock;
    proxy_set_header X-Forwarded-For $proxy_add_x_forwarded_for;
    proxy_set_header Host $http_host;
    proxy_redirect off;
    proxy_set_header X-Forwarded-Proto $scheme;
  }
&lt;/pre&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Now you can just Unicorn as a Deamon:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo unicorn_rails -c config/unicorn.rb -D&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last thing to do, and the one I dug the most is to add a scope for your rails routes file, like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre rel=&quot;Ruby&quot;&gt;
MyApp::Application.routes.draw do
  scope &#39;/myapp&#39; do
    root :to =&gt; &#39;welcome#home&#39;
    
    # other routes are always inside this block
    # ...
  end
end
&lt;/pre&gt;


&lt;p&gt;This way, your app will map a link &lt;code&gt;/myapp/welcome&lt;/code&gt;, intead of just &lt;code&gt;/welcome&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;alert&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Update 2013-08-13:&lt;/b&gt; Better solution; Easier way to make assets visible; &lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Also, we need to make rails see his in a subdirectory. At the end of your &lt;code&gt;production.rb&lt;/code&gt; file, add:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre rel=&quot;Ruby&quot;&gt;
config.relative_url_root = &quot;/myapp&quot;
&lt;/pre&gt;


&lt;p&gt;So now our app opens using &quot;/myapp&quot; subdirectory, but, hey! Where&#39;s my assets? Well, rails still believe your assets are at &quot;/assets&quot; when they should be at &quot;/myapp/assets&quot;. Let&#39;s solve this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Into your &lt;code&gt;config/applcation.rb&lt;/code&gt; file add:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre rel=&quot;Ruby&quot;&gt;
config.assets.prefix = &quot;/myapp/assets&quot;
&lt;/pre&gt;




&lt;div class=&quot;alert&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Update 2013-08-14:&lt;/b&gt; Solution for assets to work when in production; &lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;If in production environment your css or js are not being found, maybe &lt;code&gt;bundle exec rake assets:precompile RAILS_RELATIVE_URL_ROOT=/mypapp&lt;/code&gt; solves the problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now we&#39;re done. :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That was possible using this &lt;a href=&quot;http://coffeencoke.github.io/blog/2012/12/31/serving-rails-with-a-subdirectory-root-path/&quot;&gt;source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2013 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
				<link>/post/2013/08/nginx-unicorn-multiple-rails-apps</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/post/2013/08/nginx-unicorn-multiple-rails-apps</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Descobertas do cotidiano</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Descobri hoje que o caminho que estou seguindo está dependendo quase que em sua totalidade de mim (é óbvio quando te contam).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;O que realmente quero dizer necessita de mais palavras. Estou indenpendente (apenas eu, quero dizer), o que às vezes pode parecer ruim, mas, se seguido da forma correta, pode se tornar uma ótima oportunidade. Nesse ponto em que me abriram os olhos. Estou digerindo as mudanças, mas certamente foi bom ter sabido disso.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;O que quero agora é continuar a fazer um bom trabalho e alavancar projetos interessantes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2013 17:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>/post/2013/06/descobertas-do-cotidiano</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/post/2013/06/descobertas-do-cotidiano</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Errar</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Uma coisa tão frustrante mas que ensina muito, isso é errar. Estamos sempre nos deparando com situações em que por medo de errar, ficamos parados e não seguimos adiante. Errar é sempre uma opção, mas não é definido que isso vai acontecer. Tente, não desista no primeiro obstáculo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Todos nós já erramos, e ainda vamos errar, o que temos a fazer é aprender com ele e seguir adiante. Colocar na sua mente que errar é uma forma de aprendizado é importante para a vida. Sei que é bem clichê, mas os grandes cientistas, engenheiros, etc.. já erraram em algum projeto, o que fez eles terem sucesso foi sua perseverança, aprendendo mesmo no fracasso.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eu erro bastante, e sempre tenho aquele frio na barriga, mas eu tenho que continuar pois o caminho que escolhi seguir não tem como acertar tudo de primeira, e se eu acertasse tudo de primeira, ao primeiro sinal de fracasso eu fugiria, já que nunca teria sabido o que é errar antes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No vídeo abaixo, David Damberger mostra como aprender pelo erro. Assista.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe class=&quot;youtube-player&quot; type=&quot;text/html&quot; width=&quot;660&quot; height=&quot;395&quot; src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/HGiHU-agsGY&quot; allowfullscreen frameborder=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;

</description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2013 10:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>/post/2013/05/errar</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/post/2013/05/errar</guid>
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>